Contact

3523 Braewin Court Houston, TX 77068 3463976028 (Mobile) ekkarit.g@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ekkaritgaewprapun-dba-cmafmva®-3153a0151 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Financial Statement Analysis **Financial Modeling Statistics**

Certifications

Modeling

Budgeting and Forecasting Business Valuation Modeling Part II DAT207x: Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI Business Valuation Modeling Part I

Mergers & Acquisitions Financial

Ekkarit Gaewprapun, DBA, CMA, FMVA®

Accounting, finance, and analytics integrated professional with distinctive experiences in academic and business to help sustain the organization's growth.

United States

Summary

A well-educated professional in accounting, finance, and analytics integrated with over 20 years of domestic and overseas working experience wants to utilize his expertise and strategic awareness of multi-cultural environments and the needs of stakeholders to enhance the operational performance and sustain the organization's growth.

Experience

Faculty of Management Sciences, Prince of Songkla University, **Thailand**

9 years 1 month

Associate Dean for Organization Development September 2019 - January 2021 (1 year 5 months) Hat Yai, Songkla, Thailand

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

- Formulated organization strategies and implemented projects and action plans to support school vision and mission
- Monitored and supervised human resources, procurement, budgeting, accounting, and financing, public relation departments along with maintaining the efficiency of organization asset utilization and security activities
- Developed and managed international relations between institutions
- Led a team of PhDs to implement the Association Advance Collegiate Schools of Business (AACSB) Accreditation Project
- Led the SAP Project team to train and teach students and faculty members
- Collaborated with executive team members and implementation team of the Education Excellent (EdPEx) Project Implementation
- Supervised a staff of 30+ **COMMUNITY SERVICES**

- Employed the comprehensive analysis and intrinsic model to perform an ANDAMAN Health and Wellness Center Project Feasibility Study and successfully received the \$170 M government grant

Accounting and Finance Lecturer January 2012 - January 2021 (9 years 1 month) Hat Yai, Songkla, Thailand

- Lectured courses in accounting and finance at both undergraduate and graduate levels along with strategic management, statistics, business research, and corporate governance for MBA and M.S. Accountancy
- Supervised thesis students on accounting, finance, corporate governance, and capital markets, and conducted research on accounting and corporate governance

Assistant to the Dean January 2015 - August 2019 (4 years 8 months) Songkhla, Thailand

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

- Developed and maintained international relations between institutions
- Led a team of PhDs to implement the Association Advance Collegiate
 Schools of Business (AACSB) Accreditation Project
- Led the SAP Project team to train and teach students and faculty members
- Collaborated among executive team members and implementation team of the Education Excellent (EdPEx) Project Implementation
- Supervised a staff of 5

BAE Operations, LLC (a small business wholesaling auto parts in Houston, TX)

Accounting and Finance Manager
January 2005 - October 2010 (5 years 10 months)
Houston, Texas Area

- Overseed all general accounting and financial reporting, forecasting, and budgeting, and negotiated overseas suppliers to reduce production costs.
- Analyzed financial statements and created a financial model to evaluate adhoc projects

Vivienda Development Corporation (a small venture capitalist in Austin, TX closed in 2004)
Accounting and Finance Manager
February 2002 - May 2005 (3 years 4 months)
Austin, Texas Area

- Collaborated with a team of attorneys in the \$62 million dispute resolution lawsuit case
- Developed a financial model to perform the business valuation for a private company and won the \$62 million lawsuit case
- Planned and directed accounting and financial activities for the company
- Prepared financial statements, business activity reports, including ad-hoc investment projects, annual budget, and financial forecasts for the company
- Provided recommendations of all financial and accounting aspects of the current and proposed projects to the management team
- Explored investment opportunities domestically and overseas

Unisys

Information Systems Consultant 1998 - 1999 (1 year)

Bangkok Metropolitan Area, Thailand

- Managed Quality Assurance and Application Implementation Tasks for the Royal Thai Customs Department Computerized Project
- Acted as a liaison and coordinator between UNiSYS and the Royal Thai Customs Department
- Reviewed, coordinated, and assisted in implementing changes and revisions during the initial operation phase

Siemens

Accounting and Reporting Supervisor 1996 - 1997 (1 year)

Bangkok Metropolitan Area, Thailand

- Collaborated with business unit managers to prepare a budget and consolidated business reports
- Analyzed company and business unit variances and evaluated the business unit performance
- Supervised the accounting staff

Bangchak Corporation Public Company Limited
Business Analyst

1991 - 1996 (5 years)

Bangkok Metropolitan Area, Thailand

- Accomplished conversion and implementation of retail and account receivable systems
- Analyzed transportation costs and developed a hire-or-buy financial model for oil trucks

- Collaborated and acted as an internal liaison between the Information System Department, Marketing Department, Accounting and Finance Department, and other Departments to achieve company objectives
- Created document flow charts and operational guidelines for credit control staff and marketing representatives
- Managed and monitored the sales and pricing systems
- Performed follow-up evaluations on sales volume, growth, and rates of pay
- Supervised staff of 5

Education

Argosy University

Doctor of Business Administration, Accounting · (October 2003 - August 2011)

St.Edward's University

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Accounting · (2000 - 2002)

King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang

Master of Science - MS, Information Technology · (1995 - 1998)

Chiang Mai University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Accounting · (1987 - 1991)